Guide to the Allen Forte Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Analyses
  - Webern, Anton (Box 8)
    - 4 Lieder für Sopran und Orchester, Op. 13 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 6 Lieder nach Gedichten von Georg Trakl für Sopran und Kammerorchester, Op. 14 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 5 Lieder für Sopran und Kammerorchester, Op. 15 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 5 Kanons nach lateinischen Texten für Stimme und Kammerorchester, Op. 16 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Symphonie, Op. 21 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 3 Gesänge aus Viae inviae von Hildegard Jone für Stimme und Klavier, Op. 23/2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Konzert für 9 Instrumente, Op. 24 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Variationen für Klavier, Op. 27/2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Streichquartett, Op. 28/1, 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Kantate für Sopran Solo, Gemischter Chor und Orchester, Op. 29 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 5 Orchester-Stücke [Related to Op.10], No. 1, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 3 Orchester-Lieder für Stimme und Orchester, 1913-1914 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Sonate für Violoncello und Klavier (1914) (unfinished), 1914 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Sacher Stiftung - Various Webern works (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Undated; appear to be notes from lecture(s) given by Sacher Stiftung on various Webern works.
  - Wolf, Hugo (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Analysis of "Das verlassene Mägdlein".
- Correspondence, 1956-2007
  The correspondence series covers a wide range of topics. Correpondence between Forte and several prominent people in the music world are housed separately. These include Gertrud Schoenberg, Ernst Oster, David Carson Berry, and Robert Sherlaw Johnson. Other correspondence relates to a mixture of institutional, publishing, and personal topics. Dates of these letters range from 1965 to 2007, but are highly concentrated in the 1970's. Included is some correspondence of Madeleine Forte with Olivier Messiaen.
  This series is mainly arranged by date, though correspondence with selected people is separated.
  - Gertrud Schoenberg Correspondence, 1956-1967 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Ernst Oster Correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Ernst Oster Correspondence, 1967-1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re Berg, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Correspondence with Pat Hall and Brenda Dalen.
  - Correspondence with David Carson Berry re: Sator Palindrome, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Email correspondence with David Carson Berry.
  - Robert Sherlaw Johnson Correspondence, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Correspondence re Messiaen.
  - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1979-2007 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Teaching and general theory materials
  This series contains papers related to various courses and class lectures given by Forte. Some syllabi, bibliographies, and exercises and quizes are included. General theory materials, some of which may have been used for teaching, are also included in this series. This collection represents a small selection of Forte's contribution to teaching.
  This series is organized by course or lecture title, where possible.
  - General Theory Materials (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Exercise and Quiz solutions, Examples (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Course: Theory and Analysis of Atonal Music (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Course: Introduction to Schenkerian Analysis (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Course: Gershwin (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Course: Experimental Tradition in the Music of the 19th Century (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Course: Four Twentieth Century Austrian Composers (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Lecture: Webern Streichquartett (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Seminar: Orpheus, Ghent, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Ernst Oster graphs (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Copies of analytical graphs by Ernst Oster. Chopin Op. 35/iv; others unidentified.
- Manuscript drafts, writings, and lectures
  This series contains materials related to some of Forte's public lectures and writings, both published and unpublished. The materials include drafts of articles, including examples, and correspondence relating to publication. Materials about several combination lecture/recitals featuring Madeleine Forte on piano are included.
  The series is arranged by the title of the article or lecture.
  - Foreground Rhythm in Early Twentieth-Century Music, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Music Analysis 2/3: 239–68.
  - Middleground Motives in the Adagietto of Mahler's Fifth Symphony, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    19th-Century Music 8 2: 153–63.
  - Debussy and the Octatonic, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Music Analysis, Vol. 10, No. 1/2 (Mar. - Jul., 1991), pp. 125-169.
  - Debussy and the Octatonic, Appendix, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - A Schenkerian Reading of an Excerpt from Tristan und Isolde, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Musicae scientiae, Special Issue: 15–26.
  - Reflections upon the Gershwin-Berg Connection, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Musical Quarterly 83/2: 150–68.
  - Introduction to a Concert of Music by Samuel Barber (Lecture), 2002 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Wroclaw, Poland
  - Alban Berg's Piano Sonata, Op. 1: A Landmark in Early Twentieth-Century Music, 2005-2007 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Lecture, Hanyang University, November 2005. Music Analysis 26/1–2: 15–24.
  - Schoenberg's Opus 19 No. 4: A Set-Theoretic Perspective, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Around Set Theory, proceedings of a conference at IRCAM, Paris, 15–16 Oct. 2003, ed. Moreno Andreatta, Jean-Michel Bardez, and John Rahn (Sampzon, France: Editions Delatour): 49–62.
  - Alban Berg's First Atonal Composition (Lecture) (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Cole Porter's Life in Music: An Introduction to the Songs (Box 12, Folder 1)
    By A.F. and David Carson Berry
  - Harmony and harmonic fields in the the Piano Music of Debussy (Lecture) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Linear Features of Debussy's Nuages (Trois Nocturnes) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Messiaen, Livre d'orgue (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Olivier Messiaen's Early Piano Music and His Modes of Limited Transposition (Lecture) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Madeleine Forte, Pianist.
  - Schoenberg as Webern: the Three Pieces for Chamber Orchestra (Lecture) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - [Spoken commentary], in Madeleine Forte Plays Piano Music of Olivier Messiaen, with Commentary by Allen Forte (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Includes several versions of typescripts of talks given by A.F. to accompany recitals of Messiaen's work by Madeleine Forte.
  - Debussy's Interludes for Pelléas et Mélisande (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Schoenberg, Moses und Aron, Translation (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Rhythm: Miscellaneous Notes for Book (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Franz Liszt's Settings of Petrarch Sonnets (Lecture/Recital), 2005 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    Program and CD of lecture/recital, University of North Texas, February 9, 2005.
  - Schoenberg as Webern, CD of lecture, Mannes Institute, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    CD of talk given at Mannes School, New York, June 2007.
  - Article: Introduction to a theory of intervallic harmony: the summation vectors, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    Copy of article from "Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Music Theory", Tallinn, Estonia, April 2004.
  - "The Golden Thread: Octatonic Music in Webern's Early Songs" - Examples., 1996 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    In Kathryn Bailey, Webern Studies. Cambridge University Press, 1996.
  - Examples from unidentified article or lecture (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Photos, personal documents, books and scores
  This series is a collection of personal documents, photos, and autobiographical materials. Various books and scores are included here.
  This series is arranged by the type of artifact.
  - Website printouts, 2017 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Printouts of websites of Allen Forte and Madeleine Forte.
  - CDs of Interview of Allen Forte, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    CDs (2) of interview of Allen Forte by Stephen Slottow and Timothy Jackson, North Texas State University, February, 20015.
  - Photographs: Allen Forte alone (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Allen Forte with others (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: Without Allen Forte (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Marriages licenses, passport (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Autobiographical information (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Includes Curriculum Vitae and Bibliography.
  - Genealogical information (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Calendars - 2002, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Collection of newspaper articles (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Books and scores (Box 14)
    Includes: Pocket scores for various works for which analyses do not exist in this collection; Copies of Schenker, "Five Graphic Music Analyses", Cherney, "Harry Somers" (inscription to Madeliene Hsu (Forte) from Harry Somers, PhD dissertation of Hengzhan Yang (1999, incribed to Allen Forte), Score and correspondence - "The willows are new" by Chou Wen-chung, inscribed to Madeleine Forte, Guide to "Canadian Piano Music", Forte's "The Structure of Atonal Music" in Chinese, with inscription and photo of Forte with the translator, Selected music works by Luo Zhongrong; Scores, articles, dissertation (Wang Zhongyu), and books (with inscriptions) in Chinese.